<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.zennotes.ZenNotes</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>ZenNotes</name>
  <summary>Keyboard-first Markdown notes app</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      ZenNotes is a keyboard-first Markdown notes app that keeps your notes as
      ordinary Markdown files on disk — yours to own, sync, and version however
      you like.
    </p>
    <p>On top of the files you already own, it adds:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Vim-friendly editing with split and live-preview workflows</li>
      <li>Wiki-links, tags, tasks, daily notes, and full-text search</li>
      <li>Diagrams (Mermaid, TikZ), math (KaTeX), and syntax-highlighted code</li>
      <li>CSV databases with Notion-style Table and Board views over plain .csv files</li>
      <li>Archive, trash, quick capture, and a built-in command-line companion</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.zennotes.ZenNotes.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://zennotes.org/images/app.png</image>
      <caption>Editing Markdown with live preview, sidebar, and tabs</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://zennotes.org</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/ZenNotes/zennotes/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/ZenNotes/zennotes</url>
  <developer id="org.zennotes">
    <name>Adib Hanna</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.13.1" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging-only patch: adds a native .rpm for Fedora, RHEL, and openSUSE (x64 and arm64) alongside the existing package formats. No application changes since 2.13.0.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.13.0" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>Inline Excalidraw drawing embeds (![[drawing.excalidraw]]), a choice of where new drawings and databases are created, a confirmation toast after exporting a note to PDF, a toggle for a solid non-blinking cursor, and the Kanagawa Paper Ink theme, plus fixes for Excalidraw following custom themes, strikethrough crossing out math, editor focus when opening daily notes, and calendar task-list sync.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.12.0" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Custom Kanban statuses and a board for any inline @field, a two-way Vim clipboard so p/P paste from the system clipboard, and one-move clearing of selected tag filters, plus fixes for CircuiTikZ rendering on desktop, shortcuts and Vim keys after the app sits idle, keyboard focus returning to the editor when a pane closes, and drawing image export.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.11.0" date="2026-07-07">
      <description>
        <p>Task forwarding (the bullet-journal migrate gesture) and monthly notes, plus @time/@now and @ note-linking macros, o/O list continuation in Vim, :saveas, and a large batch of Vim and editor fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.10.0" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Transclusion — embed a note's rendered content inline with ![[Note]] in the reading view and PDF export — plus backlinks for standard Markdown links, reorderable database columns, opt-in persistent self-host sessions, a CLI renamed to zn so it no longer clashes with Zen Browser, and nine fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.0" date="2026-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>Bring your own theme — author full CSS themes, layer quick overrides on any theme, or recolor and resize with no-code Quick tweaks — plus the new Rosé Pine theme, per-vault view settings with synced workspaces, themed PDF export, and fixes across PDF export, tables, Vim, and keymaps.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.0" date="2026-06-25">
      <description>
        <p>A windowed sidebar that stays fast on huge vaults, a calmer redesigned Settings page, a new home view with your recent notes and today's tasks, Obsidian Excalidraw import, and image-rendering fixes in PDF export and Live Preview.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.0" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>Link straight to your CSV databases with wikilinks, Notion-style slash commands in Quick Capture, and editor fixes (per-note undo, wikilinks in code, document outline).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.0" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>A portable plain-text config file you can sync across machines, manual task reordering in notes and on the Tasks page, faster vault reopening, and remappable table navigation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.0" date="2026-06-22">
      <description>
        <p>Real Markdown highlighting, system-wide quick capture on Wayland, manual note ordering, and the Kanagawa theme.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.4.0" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>Maintenance release with editor and vault improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.3.0" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Maintenance release with editor and vault improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
